Opposites react.
Elemental is a family, fantasy, comedy film directed by Peter Sohn.
In a city where fire, water, land and air residents live together, a fiery young woman and a
go-with-the-flow guy will discover something elemental: how much they have in common.
Ember (voice), played by Leah Lewis.
Wade (voice), played by Mamoudou Athie.
Bernie (voice), played by Ronnie del Carmen.
Cinder (voice), played by Shila Ommi.
Gale (voice), played by Wendi McLendon-Covey.
Brook (voice), played by Catherine O'Hara.
Elemental is a 2023 American animated romantic comedy-drama film
produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by Peter Sohn and produced by Denise Ream, it was written
by Sohn, John Hoberg, Kat Likkel, and Brenda Hsueh.
The film stars the voices of Leah Lewis, Mamoudou Athie, Ronnie del
Carmen, Shila Ommi, Wendi McLendon-Covey, and Catherine O'Hara.
Set in a world inhabited by anthropomorphic elements of nature, the story follows fire element Ember Lumen and water element Wade
Ripple, who spend time together in the city while trying to save a convenience store owned by Ember's father, Bernie.
Development of Elemental began when Sohn pitched the concept to Pixar based on
the idea of whether fire and water could ever connect or not.
The film draws inspiration from Sohn's youth, growing up as the son of immigrants in New York City during the 1970s, highlighting the city's distinct cultural and
ethnic diversity while the story is inspired by romantic films such as Guess Who's Coming to Dinner (1967), Moonstruck (1987), and Amélie (2001).
The production team conducted research by spending many hours watching
point-of-view city tours on YouTube like Venice and Amsterdam for inspiration.
Animation tools were utilized to design the visual effects and
appearance of each character, particularly its main characters.
Production on Elemental lasted for seven years, both in the studio and at
the filmmakers' homes, on an estimated $200 million budget.
Thomas Newman composed the score, and Lauv wrote and
performed the song "Steal the Show".
The film is dedicated to Pixar animators Ralph Eggleston,
Thomas Gonzales, Amber Martorelli, and J.
Garrett Sheldrew, all of whom died in 2022.
Elemental debuted out of competition as the closing film at the 76th Cannes Film Festival on May 27, 2023,
and was released in the United States on June 16 in RealD 3D, 4DX, and Dolby Cinema formats.
Despite initially opening below projections, the film was ultimately considered by
analysts to be a sleeper hit and grossed $496.4 million worldwide.
It was nominated for several awards, including the Academy Award for Best Animated
Feature and the Golden Globe Award for Best Animated Feature Film.
The film explores themes of fire, earth, computer
animation, duringcreditsstinger, elements.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.